Hello again.
In this part we will be talking about mobile, NFC and security.
The main topic here will be the secure element.
So the use of the NFC option in the mobile phones is increasing day after day.
The purpose of that is to make our life easier.
It offers a range of benefits that make it an attractive option for businesses and consumers alike.
One of the key advantages is convenience.
With NFC mobile, users can simply tap their phone to a compatible device to make a payment, access
information or perform other tasks.
This eliminates the need for physical cards or other devices.
Streamlining the user experience and making transactions faster and easier than ever before.
More than that, a mobile is ergonomic, easy to use, has a test screen, can be characterized by different
way of connectivity.
Another major benefit of NFC mobile is security.
By using encrypted communication protocols and secure authentication methods, NFC mobile ensures that
sensitive data is protected from unauthorized access.
This makes it popular a choice for applications such as mobile payments, where security is of paramount
importance.
Here is a table of comparison between what we can do using a mobile phone and the contactless cards.
When we say contactless card, we mean pick.
We can see clearly that when the services are in the NFC mobile, it offers more advantages and facilitate
the tasks because of the interaction with the applications installed in the mobile phone.
For example, for transportation, we can just use our NFC subscription card to use the bus or the metro.
But when we have the subscription integrated to our mobile through an application, it may offer us
the possibility to follow the bus in real time and geolocated traffic information.
Most important thing about NFC tags or pick contactless cards is security.
It's good to have all these services, but with that we need to protect our information and especially
our transaction.
The first NFC applications were developed for payment and secure access control.
Also, NFC has often been compared to contactless security, even if its scope goes well beyond.
NFC technology is adapted to meet the security constraints of contactless.
So what are the threats for this kind of communication?
By the principle of propagation of radio frequency waves, any contactless transmission can be listened
to.
But understanding, interpreting, modifying, or altering the content of the message transmitted is
a completely different story.
NFC technology has intrinsic advantages for securing applications.
Applications such as mobile payment require the examination of all vulnerabilities.
Interceptions, corruption or modification of data, and problems linked to the theft of mobile devices.
They have been resolved in the same way as those linked to the security of contactless bank cards,
either at the physical layer or at the applications layers.
So what about tax security?
Passive NFC tags are just a memory associated with an antenna, possibly with a processor to manage
communication and cryptography.
Tags can be secured by encrypting data, verifying its integrity, and preventing tag tearing, for
example.
Data encryption.
The data can be saved encrypted in the tag memory.
It's up to the reader to decrypt it with the application.
Data can be also encrypted by the tag.
In the case of exchange with applications of different types, in this case the tag must have a cryptographic
processor which is more expensive.
Second thing is data integrity.
In order to verify that the data has not been modified, or that the tag has not been replaced by a
fake, there are integrity verification schemes which are based on a secure signature.
For example, RTD signature of the NFC forum or an integrity check using a web service.
Third thing is the anti pooling.
It's to prevent their tearing.
The tags can be sealed in the material non-conductive of course, of the tagged object, and can include
self-destruction devices in the event of physical tearing called anti tearing.
So what about secure mobile?
NFC payment, transport and strong authentication applications have understood all the benefits they
could derive from the intrinsic security of NFC.
This was not enough to guarantee strong application security.
Secure platforms for mobile services have been around for many years.
The mobile phone architecture is equipped with tools to ensure secure interaction between applications
and with the multiple players in mobile systems.
The architecture is mainly based on two elements the application Execution environment and the trusted
execution Environment, which have been specified by organizations such as GSMa or Global Platform.
In fact, the IEEE Application Execution Environment is not a secure space, but it allows the controlled
execution of application within the framework of complex operating system.
This is where most of the attacks and viruses in smartphones are concentrated.
The te trusted execution environment.
Is a space secured by hardware and software which resides in the microprocessor of the phone.
Its role is to protect secure data and applications from internal and external attacks, ensuring their
separation.
And controlled access.
These two elements may be sufficient.
These two elements, I mean, a and t, may be sufficient to guarantee the security of applications
permanently connected to the mobile network.
They prove insufficient in many NFC use cases where the transaction is done locally between two NFC
devices.
Thus appeared the need to create other security bricks to cover the needs of NFC service providers,
such as banking, transport or access control services.
These security bricks must meet security certifications such as Common Criteria in the NFC ecosystem.
This role is carried out by secure elements and trusted service managers.
So what is this secure element to carry out secure transactions?
A certain number of operations must be protected.
Such as identification, authentication, signature or validation by Pin code.
This is the role of the secure element, which offers cryptographic processing services and secure memory
to store secret information like passwords, encryption keys, personal data, etc., etc..
The Secure Element is a highly secure microcontroller that uses the same security principle as the chips
of bank cards.
It provides transaction authentication, data protection, and backup functions for secure applications
such as payment access control or electronic identity control in a mobile phone.
It can take several forms a SIM card, a component of the telephone or an SD memory, or even in some
cases, a server on the internet network.
This.
The form factor of this secure element obviously has a great impact in term of markets because the actor
who because it's the actor who controls access to the secure element, can control and monetize the
relationship with applications, issuers and their clients.
Therefore, it's up to the service provider to choose the type of secure element that best corresponds
to its business model and the consumer's expectations.